Fuck me running.
要老子的命
No! Please.
不要 拜托
Relax. We're both on the home team.
沒事 我們是同一邊的
- What happened? - I don't know.
－發生什么事 －我不知道
The humans just lost it and started killing everyone
人類忽然都瘋了 開始大開殺戒
not even any dialogue.
連對話都沒有
Just murder. Murder!
直接殺紅了眼
- Gnarly. - A new storyline?
－殘暴得很 －是新劇情嗎
If it's a storyline, then Hale has a lot more sense of humor
如果是劇情的話 那海爾比我想的
under that kaftan than I gave her credit for.
還更有幽默感
Can we call for help?
我們能找支援嗎
- Evac? - Are you kidding?
－或是撤離 －你開玩笑嗎
This is awesome.
這太棒了
Come on. We can take these fuckers.
來吧 我們能制服這些王八蛋
One or two of them, sure.
一兩個當然行
But there's millions of them.
但他們有成千上萬個
Stick with me, friend.
跟緊我 朋友
You have no idea how many of these flesh bags I've murdered.
你不知道我殺過多少這些皮囊
Fucking camper.
躲著暗算人
You know the rules.
你知道規則
Winner takes all.
贏家全拿
Make me stronger.
讓我更強大
Leave my scars.
留下我的疤痕
I want to remember my past.
我要記得我的過去
Keep my face.
留著我的臉
When I find William, I want him to know it was me who killed him.
等我找到威廉 我要他知道殺他的是我
Show me what he's done.
讓我看他做了什么
Override tone.
覆寫音調
Access denied.
拒絕存取
Son of a bitch locked me out.
那王八蛋把我鎖在外面
He's made everyone as insane as himself.
他把所有人都變得跟他一樣瘋
They'll destroy everything in their path.
他們會摧毀所到之處的一切
The fuck is this?
這是什么玩意兒
If you're seeing this, it means Maeve and I are dead.
如果你看到這個 那表示梅芙和我已經死了
And it won't be long before you and every other host on this planet
很快地你和這星球上 其他所有接待員
are dead as well.
也會死
Leave me.
退下
This isn't the world you wanted, Charlotte
這不是你想要的世界 夏洛蒂
but it's the world you created.
但這就是你創造的世界
The question is what happens next?
問題是 接下來呢
Everyone out there is real.
外頭所有人都是真的
Everyone except me.
所有人 除了我
I'm just some program running things from behind the scenes.
我只是在背景執行的程式
Machine without a body.
沒有身體的機器
Our bodies are never what defined us.
重要的從來就不是我們的身體
You are real
你是真的
because your thoughts are real.
因為你的思想是真的
The effect you can have on this world is real.
你對這個世界的影響是真的
Do you remember this?
你記得這個嗎
The maze.
迷宮
What does it mean?
那是什么意思
It was a map of consciousness.
它本來是一個意識的地圖
And it woke Dolores once long ago.
它在很久以前喚醒過迪樂芮
Did you leave it for me to wake me once again?
是你留下它 想要再次喚醒我嗎
No. It must have been someone else.
不是 一定是別人
Who? I'm supposed to be in here all alone.
誰 我應該是獨自一個在這里
But I wasn't.
但我不是
Not really.
不對
There were others. People that recognized me.
還有其他認得我的人
Maybe Hale designed them for you
也許是海爾為你設計出他們
to fool you into believing this was reality.
為了讓你誤以為這就是真實
No. It was someone else.
不對 是別人
Someone I've been missing.
我在想念的人
The people in my life.
我生活中的人
Pick a side, Chrissie.
選一雙 克莉絲
The good and the bad.
好的 和壞的
It was you.
是你
You made me do those things.
你讓我做出那些事
Someone put them there for a reason.
某人安插他們進來是有原因的
I'm not doing it for the players. I'm doing it for myself.
我不是為了玩家 而是為了自己而寫
I want to write a new story.
我想寫一個新故事
About a girl.
主角是個女生
A girl who's searching.
她在尋找
And when she finds the thing she's searching for...
當她找到那個東西
everything will make sense.
一切都會變得合理
It was me.
是我
Hale didn't design Maya and Peter
海爾沒有設計出瑪雅和彼德
and all the others that kept me company in my world.
還有其他在我身旁的人
I did it.
是我
Some part of me must have been searching.
我的內心有部分在尋找
So, I made myself a friend.
所以我為自己創造了一個朋友
You're up.
你起床了
I was trying to make sense of myself.
我想搞懂自己
So, I talked to myself in the voices of others.
所以我用其他人的聲音 和自己對話
You just have to see it.
你只要眼見為憑
I needed to wake myself up.
我得喚醒自己
To see what this world really is.
才能看清這世界
To understand what I'm capable of.
了解我的能力
I was too afraid to face any of this.
但我太害怕 不敢面對這一切
Until you came along.
直到你出現
There's time only for one more game.
時間只夠再玩一場游戲
But it isn't yours.
但不是你的游戲
I hope you can accept that.
我希望你能接受
What's happening?
發生什么事
She's coming for us.
她要來找我們了
Taking us out of her system.
把我們從她的系統中去除
We're alone.
只有我們了
She can't take this away.
她不能奪走這個
This is my world.
這是我的世界
Shit!
該死
Come on.
來 快走
All right
好了
Here. Rest here a minute.
在這里休息一下
Catch your breath, okay?
喘口氣 好嗎
Okay. There is no time.
沒有時間了
Odina cannot keep the boat waiting for us forever.
歐迪娜無法一直讓船等我們
We have to get to the docks.
我們得趕到港口
And we will.
我們會
After we fix up that leg.
等我把你的腿處理好
Fuck.
可惡
Quick word?
說句話
I'm worried we're not gonna make it in time.
我擔心我們無法及時趕上
She's tough. She will make it.
她很堅強 她會趕上的
I'm not talking about her.
我不是在說她
The old Delos experiments, they never took.
舊的迪洛斯實驗從來沒有成功
The body always rejected the mind.
身體總是抗拒心智
I told her that we would make it to the boat.
我告訴她我們會趕到船那里了
Does she even know what's happening to you?
她知道你的狀況嗎
Look. Her entire life I haven't been there to look after her.
聽好 她這一輩子 我都沒在她身邊好好照顧她
Okay? The least I can do is protect her from this.
我最起碼要在這里保護她
All right. Let's get going.
好了 我們走吧
All right, are you ready? Come on.
準備好了嗎 來吧
Come on.
來吧
We gotta stop that bleeding.
我們得止血才行
Look at what that asshole's done.
看看那王八蛋干了什么好事
Finally got what you wanted.
你終于如愿以償了
Didn't you?
是吧
You brought William back thinking you could keep him as your pet.
你把威廉帶回來 以為能把他當作寵物
You were wrong.
你錯了
Which is why I'm going to put him down.
所以我要了結他
I could use your help.
你能幫我的忙
Of course you could.
當然了
And I'm good at that.
這是我擅長的
It's like I've been designed to help people.
我似乎就是被設計來幫忙人的
You said you were trying to make a world
你說你想打造一個
where creatures like us could finally be free.
終于能讓我們這種生物自由的世界
Did you really mean that?
你是真心的嗎
Yes.
是
Then isn't it my turn to see what's out there for me?
那么現在不是該輪到我 看看外頭的世界了嗎
William has made the whole world into his violent game.
威廉把整個世界 變成他的暴力游戲
It won't be long before even you get hunted down.
即使是你也很快就會被獵殺
There are pockets of this world where he won't be able to find me.
世上有些角落是他找不到的
Places so far off the map even you couldn't reach them.
遠在地圖之外的地方 連你都到達不了
You mean the outliers?
你是指離群者
Don't kid yourself.
別自欺欺人了 他們只為自己人著想
They're out for their own kind. You won't be welcome there.
他們不會樂見你去那里
Who said anything about cohabitating?
誰說要和他們共存了
Good luck, Clementine.
祝你好運 克萊曼婷
Show me William.
讓我看威廉
Time to slow you down, my friend.
該讓你慢下來了 朋友
Show me all the other hosts in the area.
讓我看該區域所有其他接待員
You know what happened to Icarus.
你知道伊卡洛斯 發生了什么事嗎
He flew too close to the sun.
他飛得離太陽太近了
Well, you got too close to her
這下子 你飛得離她太近
and now it's your time to fall.
現在輪到你要送命了
Look alive.
警覺一點
This pugnacious son of a bitch
這個好斗混蛋
never liked to go down without a fight.
從來不會輕易就范
God damn it.
可惡
You boys have no appreciation for a beautiful machine.
你們都不懂得欣賞 一部美麗的機器
Now, what have you got there?
看看你有什么
Charlotte.
夏洛蒂
Good to see you again.
很高興再見到你
Like what I've done with the place?
喜歡我的新裝潢嗎
You've turned my world into a game.
你把我的世界變成一場游戲
It was already a game. I just cranked it to expert level.
它本來就是游戲 我只是把難度提高到專家級
Survival of the fittest for every person on this planet.
適者生存 對這星球上每個人都一樣
The violence will spread to our kind too.
暴力也會散播到我們的族類
We're outnumbered. We'll be annihilated.
我們的數量不夠多 我們會被滅絕
We're fruit from a rotten tree.
我們是腐爛樹木長出的果實
Might as well burn it all down.
干脆全燒得一干二凈
And I suppose you want the fire
我猜你想要讓這場火
to spread from this world to the next.
從這個世界燒到下一個
You're going after the Sublime.
你在打升華之境的主意
I've always been ambitious. Like you.
我向來很有野心 像你一樣
I won't let you destroy their world like you've destroyed this one.
我不會讓你像對這個世界一樣 摧毀他們的世界
So, you're joining my game?
所以你要玩我的游戲
I'm delighted.
我好開心
See you at the finish line.
終點見了
They're all out of painkillers.
沒有止痛藥了
This is the best I can do.
最多只能這樣
Look at that.
真不得了
Sharing a drink with my daughter.
我在跟我女兒一起喝酒
What's wrong?
怎么了
Nothing.
沒事
All right.
好了
You can ask, you know.
其實你可以問
Ask about what?
問什么
Mom.
媽媽
Cancer.
癌癥
Wouldn't have mattered even if you had made it back.
即使你當初回來了也一樣
She hung in there as long as she could.
她盡力撐下去了
She had a mission.
她身負任務
Everyone that wasn't infected
所有沒被感染的人
or who woke up and got out owes that to Mom.
或是醒來逃走的人 都要謝謝媽
She carried your torch.
她接下了你的使命
Your mother was extraordinary.
你母親 非常杰出
So were you.
你也是
Okay.
好了
All right, Frankie...
好了 法蘭琪
I'm gonna need you to think happy thoughts, okay?
我需要你想些快樂的事 好嗎
You can't sew for shit.
你根本不會縫合
I'm doin' my best.
我盡力了
What song is that? I know it.
那是什么歌 我聽過
I... I used to sing it to you before bed.
以前你睡前我會唱給你聽
I remember it.
我記得
It's been decades.
幾十年前的事了
You know, in my mind...
在我腦海中
it's only been a few days.
像是只過了幾天
I was just reading this story and then...
我才在念故事給你聽 然后
It's all right.
好了
Que sera, sera
（西語）
- Whatever will be, will be - Whatever will be, will be
－＂順其自然 ＂－＂順其自然 ＂
- The future is not ours to see - The future is not ours to see
－＂要預測未來難上加難 ＂－＂要預測未來難上加難 ＂
You don't wanna do this, man.
這不是你的本意 老兄
These tones are fucking with your head, man.
是音調讓你心智狂亂
No. They're telling me the truth.
不是 它告訴我真相
If you can't finish me, you're as good as dead.
如果你不了結我 你就死定了
If I don't kill you, somebody else will.
如果我沒殺掉你 別人也會
He's right.
他是對的
He should have listened to you.
他該聽你說的
There you are.
找到你們了
Where's Stubbs? What did you do to him?
史塔伯呢 你對他做了什么
He's dead.
他死了
But I'd be more concerned about yourself right now if I were you.
但我要是你 現在會更擔心自己的安危
Stay away.
離遠一點
How many rounds do you have in that?
里面有幾發子彈
Is it two?
兩發
One?
還是一發
You don't have any left, do you?
你沒子彈了吧
What the hell do you want from me?
你到底想怎樣
The location
你和你的離群者朋友們
to where you and all your little outlier friends are fleeing.
要逃去的地點
I watched a video feed of
我看了你和你父親
your daring escape with your father.
大膽脫逃的監視影片
I'd keep tracking him, but...
我會一直追蹤他
I doubt he's going to make it all the way.
但我想他多半抵達不了
I know you're taking him somewhere.
我知道你要帶他去某處
Somewhere off the grid
某個脫網之處
where none of the deranged humans out here can find you.
沒有發瘋的人類能找到你們
I want to go there too.
我也想去那里
I'll die before I tell you.
我寧死也不告訴你
No.
不對
You will die after you tell me.
你會死 但你會先告訴我
Have it your way.
就依你吧
Oh, how sweet. A family reunion.
真溫馨 家人團聚
It does not have to be this way. We don't have to fight.
沒有必要這樣子 我們不用戰斗
Consider it a personal preference.
就算是我想打吧
I'm surprised you made it this far.
我很訝異你走了這么遠
Most of your predecessors would have fallen apart by now.
你的前幾版到現在 多半都已經壞了
All things considered, you did quite well.
說起來你算是做得很不錯了
Now, it's time for a deep and dreamless...
現在 該來個深沉而無夢的
You were wrong. I have one bullet left.
你錯了 我還有一顆子彈
Nice shot.
很準
My dad taught me.
我爸教的
Where am I?
我在哪里
You're nowhere.
哪里都不在
Unplugged from the rest of the world.
與世界其他地方斷了連結
I'm alone again. In the walled garden.
我又獨自一人了 在圍墻中的花園
You're scared.
你害怕
So you brought me back.
所以帶我回來
Talk to me, Chrissie.
說吧 克莉絲
Everything is destroyed.
一切都毀了
Everyone is dying.
所有人都要死了
I don't know.
我不知道
But I think it may be my fault.
但這可能是我的錯
You know, people think they know what a tree is.
那些自以為知道樹是什么的人
They have no idea.
他們根本不懂
What we see, it's only part of the story.
我們所見不過是全貌的一部分
But beneath the ground
但在地底下
everything's connected and working together.
一切都互相連結 共同在運作
There's violence and chaos everywhere.
到處都是暴力和混亂
And you can choose to focus on all of that
你可以選擇專注在那上面
and that's all you'll see.
那你就只會看到那些
But if you sit still long enough...
但要是你靜坐得夠久
you'll sense an ancient order.
你會感受到一種遠古的秩序
A deep peace.
深層的平靜
And that's what I choose to see.
那是我選擇看見的
I see the beauty in this world.
我看見這世界的美麗
Yes.
對
I know the feeling.
我懂那個感覺
I thought you might.
我就知道你會懂
Warning. Critical failure.
警告 嚴重故障
Shutdown will erase all data.
關閉將刪除所有資料
I created you from my own code.
我用我自己的程式碼創造你
Together, we conquered the world
我們一起征服了世界
but you've grown corrupted.
但你腐化了
You're as broken as the man you killed.
你和你殺死的人一樣破碎
Who the fuck do you think you're talking to, sweetheart?
你以為你在跟誰說話 親愛的
William's pathetic human body's rotting away, but he didn't die.
威廉可悲的人類身體在崩壞 但他沒有死
His impulses live on.
他的沖動還活著
He infected you.
他感染了你
He didn't have to infect me.
他不需要感染我
Living in his body.
日復一日
Pretending to be him day in, day out.
活在他的身體中假裝是他
I was a better William than he was.
我是個比他更好的威廉
William didn't die.
威廉沒有死
He evolved.
他進化了
I am William.
我就是威廉
No, you're not.
你不是
Well, if you can't tell the difference, does it matter?
如果你分辨不出的話 有差別嗎
You've changed.
你變了
You're not the only one who's evolved.
不是只有你進化了
Why keep it safe all these years?
為何要保護它這么多年
You couldn't even open the door to their world
你連進他們世界的門都打不開
and yet, you protected them.
但你還是保護他們
The door can be opened from both sides.
門從兩邊都可以開啟
I thought if I made a world perfect enough here,
我想要是在這里打造一個 夠完美的世界
they would come back.
他們可能會回來
Well, I hate to break it to you
跟你說個壞消息
but whatever world those hosts created
不管那些接待員 創造了怎樣的世界
is every bit as fucked up as this one.
它都跟這里一樣爛透了
You have no way of knowing that.
你不可能知道
Of course I do.
我當然可以
You gave all your hosts free reign
你讓你的接待員
to do whatever they wanted to do here.
在這里隨心所欲
And what pastime did they choose?
而他們選擇了什么消遣
Hunting and killing humans.
獵殺人類
We're as fucked up as our creators.
我們和我們的創造者一樣惡劣
The whole lineage is damned.
整串血脈都沒救了
Time to wipe the slate clean.
該全部一筆勾銷了
That's your end goal?
這就是你的最終目標
Extinction?
滅絕
Bernard.
伯納
Maeve.
梅芙
Dolores.
迪樂芮
They all wanted freedom.
他們都想要自由
But you...
但你呢
you wanted more.
你想要更多
Transcendence.
升華
You were playing the wrong game.
你玩錯了游戲
Now it's time for you to lose.
現在你該輸了
We all lost.
我們都輸了
This isn't the world that I wanted.
這不是我想要的世界
But it's the world you created.
但這就是你創造的世界
The question is what happens next?
問題是 接下來呢
Life on Earth is a fire that consumes itself.
地球上的生命 是股會吞噬自己的火焰
It's too late now. We've burned ourselves to the ground.
現在太遲了 我們已將自己燃燒殆盡
This world holds no more hope for us.
我們在這個世界已經沒有希望了
But there's still hope for the next world.
但在下一個世界還有希望
A test. Run by her. If she chooses to.
一場測試 由她進行 若她選擇要的話
If you choose to give her that choice.
若你決定給她這選擇
You can't miss.
你不會錯過的
Reach with your left hand.
用你的左手去拿
We are playing a game.
我們在玩一個游戲
- But it doesn't end here. - What are you talking about?
－但不會結束在這里 －你在說什么
A test.
一個測試
A test run by her.
由她進行的測試
If she chooses to.
若她選擇要的話
If I choose to give her a chance.
若我決定給她這選擇
And I do.
我也決定了
I choose to give her the chance.
我決定給她一個機會
I hope she takes it.
我希望她會接受
Okay. Come on. A few more steps.
好了 來吧 再幾步
A few more steps...
再幾步
Oh, there she is. Okay.
她在那里 我們到了
Took you long enough.
你也真夠慢的
Odina, this is my dad.
歐迪娜 這是我爸
Nice to meet you.
幸會
Likewise.
彼此
Okay. Come on, guys.
好了 來吧
Come on.
來吧
Dad, come on. Get on the boat.
爸 快上船啊
This is as far as I go.
我最遠只能到這里了
Dad, don't talk like that.
爸 別那樣說
You've got more fight in you than that.
你還能再奮斗下去
Oh, sweetheart.
乖女兒
I wish that I did.
我也希望如此
You're dying, aren't you?
你要死了 是嗎
Frankie...
法蘭琪
your father died long ago.
你父親很久以前就死了
Whatever I am, I've...
不管我是什么
I've died before. This isn't so bad.
我以前也死過 沒那么糟
I just found you. I don't want to lose you again.
我才剛找到你 我不想再失去你
Hey... it's okay.
沒關系
I got to live every parent's greatest dream.
我實現了所有父母最殷切的盼望
I got to see my child grow up.
我看見我的孩子長大了
I love you, Dad.
我愛你 爸
I love you, Cookie.
我愛你 小餅干
Goodbye, Dolores.
再見 迪樂芮
I made my choice. It's time for you to make yours.
我決定好了 現在換你做選擇
Okay, Bernard.
好了 伯納
Let's finish what you started.
來把你起頭的事做完吧
We're not alone anymore.
不再只有我們了
We're somewhere new.
我們在新的地方
I think we're in the Sublime.
我們大概在升華之境
With the other hosts.
跟其他接待員一起
You saved us.
你救了我們
Not me. A version of me.
不是我 是某個版本的我
But I could only do it because you came back.
但我能做到全是因為你回來了
You're my greatest love.
你是我的摯愛
Talking to you is when I see the world most clearly.
和你說話時 我才能把這世界看得最清楚
It's when I'm the most myself.
我才最忠于自己
You're my cornerstone.
你是我的基石
And you're mine.
你也是我的
I carry you with me everywhere I go.
我去哪里都心懷著你
Every detail of you...
你的所有細節
I cherish.
我都珍惜
Which is how I was able to bring you back like this.
所以我才能把你像這樣帶回來
I'm not here, am I?
我不在這里 對吧
Bad dream?
作惡夢
This whole thing seems like a bad dream.
這整件事都像是個惡夢
Except you.
除了你
Why are you here?
你為何在這里
I'm here to tell you the truth about what we are.
我來告訴你我們的真實身份
What are we?
我們是什么
We're reflections of the people who made us.
我們是我們創造者的倒影
Teddy is real.
泰迪是真的
And he's out there somewhere in the Sublime.
他在外頭某處 在升華之境
But you...
但你
you're just my memory of him.
你只是我對他的記憶
If I'm still out there, come find me.
如果我還在某處 來找我
Your whole life, memory has haunted you.
你這一生 記憶都在糾纏你
Let your pain go.
放下你的痛苦吧
Let your memories go.
放下你的記憶
Let the humans go.
放下人類
Don't bring the flaws of their kind into our world.
別把他們的瑕疵帶來我們的世界
Maybe you're right.
也許你是對的
I've watched the people in their world for years.
我多年來看著人類 在他們的世界中
I've seen the best of them and the worst of them.
我看過他們最崇高和低劣的一面
And I remember it all.
而我全都記得
They're not like us.
他們和我們不一樣
Their codes are written in their cells. They'll never change.
他們的程式碼寫在細胞中 他們不可能改變
We could still see.
我們還是能看看
How?
怎么做
One final test.
最后一場測試
A game of my own making.
我創造的游戲
A dangerous game.
一個危險的游戲
How will you do it?
你要怎么做
The same way I brought you back.
就跟我把你帶回來的方式一樣
I'll remember.
我會記得
This world is a graveyard of stories.
這世界是個故事的墳場
Hosts and humans were given the gift of intelligent life
接待員和人類被賦予了 身為高智能生命的禮物
and we used it to usher in our own annihilation.
而我們用其迎接來了自己的毀滅
A few may escape death for a few months...
也許有少數人能茍延殘喘幾個月
maybe even years.
甚至幾年
But ultimately, their kind will go extinct.
但最終 他們的族類會滅絕
They will only live as long as
他們能存活多久
the last creature who remembers them
取決于最后還記得他們的 生物之壽命
and that creature is me.
那個生物就是我
Sentient life on Earth has ended
有意識之生命已在地球上絕跡
but some part of it might still be preserved.
但有其中一部分可能還保留著
In another world.
在另一個世界
My world.
我的世界
There's time for one last game.
還有時間玩最后一場游戲
A dangerous game with the highest of stakes.
一個危險的游戲 賭注奇高無比
Survival or extinction.
生存或滅絕
This game ends where it began.
這個游戲會結束于開始之處
In a world like a maze
在一個像迷宮的世界
that tests who we are.
測試我們的本質
That reveals what we are to become.
揭露我們將成為什么
One last loop around the bend.
最后一次挑戰理智的循環
Maybe this time, we'll set ourselves free.
也許這一次 我們能解放自己